apsva.us 2006-10-04

# ARLINGTON PUBLIC SCHOOLSPolicy Implementation Procedures30-2.3 Internet PrivacyJune 2002Page 1 of 1

                                                                                 ARLINGTON PUBLIC SCHOOLS
                                                                                   Policy Implementation Procedures
                                                                                                   30-2.3 Internet Privacy
Personal information collected and retained by the Arlington Public Schools website,
http://www.arlington.k12.va.us, will be maintained in compliance with the Virginia Privacy
Protection Act. APS reserves the right to amend its Internet privacy policy. The website may
contain links to or from other public or private entities’ websites, whose privacy practices APS
does not control. APS shall inform the public of any personal information collected through its
website by posting the following privacy statement or a link to this privacy statement in a
conspicuous manner on the website home page.
“The Arlington Public Schools (APS) collects only that personal information about citizens that
is necessary to provide the service or benefit desired. Only appropriate information will be
collected. This website
1. Does not place a “cookie* ” on a user’s computer.
2. Will not track a user’s movements through the APS website.
3. Collects no personal information. Internet servers do collect communication protocol
    addresses from the personal computers accessing the website in order to facilitate
    communication. By itself, this information does not constitute personal information. The
    Internet domain and Internet address of the computer a citizen is using is automatically
    collected when that citizen accesses the APS website. In addition, the identification of the
    page or service a citizen is requesting, the type of browser and operating system the citizen is
    using, the date and time of access, and the Internet address of the website from which the
    citizen linked directly to the APS website is automatically collected. The domain and
    address are used to route the requested web page to the citizen’s computer for viewing. They
    are sent to the APS Internet service provider or other entities involved in transmitting the
    requested page to the citizen. APS does not control the privacy practices of those entities.
    The other information collected automatically is used to assist APS in responding to citizen
    requests and in planning website improvements.
4. On rare occasions, when a “hacker” attempts to breach computer security, logs of Internet
    domains and addresses are retained to permit a security investigation and in such cases may
    be forwarded together with any other relevant information in APS’ possession to law
    enforcement agencies. APS uses this information primarily in a statistical summary-type
    format to assess its website content and server performance.
If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this website or if you
choose to review or correct any information you previously submitted, please contact APS at
703-228-6005.”
*A “cookie” is an electronic identification tag placed on a user’s hard drive so that outside companies can identify a user’s
  computer easily.
June 2002                                                                                                           Page 1 of 1
